welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes no time for intros let's get
into it the American Revolution causes
leads into two fields of thought
philosophical and direct causes this
video is on the philosophical causes so
if you remember back in unit 2 I said
this the enlightenment also started in
Europe which was an intellectual
movement of verason and science this
would have a heavy influence on
colonists later when the revolution
would start so around the same time all
these taxes are being imposed by the
British the enlightenment is running
rampant through Europe and because of
the Atlantic World these Enlightenment
IDE deals get spread to the British
colonies first we have John Lock who
argued in his book second treaties that
every person is born with a natural
right to life liberty and property and
this might sound familiar as this exact
idea is written into our Declaration of
Independence then we have Jean Jac rouso
who argued in his book the social
contract that when people live under a
government they enter into a so-called
social contract where they give away
some of their freedoms for government
benefits and finally we have Baron de
MCU who argued in his book the spirit of
laws that there should be a separation
of government into three branches and
there were plenty of philosophes like
Vol and Hobbs who argued against
European government style and favored a
more Republican style government this
all caused colonists to believe in the
superiority of Republican forms of
government and natural rights of
citizens this is best Illustrated in a
book by Thomas Payne named Common Sense
where he directly petitioned colonists
to declare independence from Britain and
also arguing that a Republican
government based on the consent of the
people was the best form of government
and that the British Monarchy was
tyrannical in har har F to the colony's
interests and I want you to think about
this for a second by calling it common
sense pain made radical ideas like
Dearing Independence and rejecting
monarchy seem obvious and reasonable to
Everyday colonists all of this
Enlightenment thought including this
book by pain would be engraved in the
ideas of the Declaration of Independence
written by Thomas Jefferson in 1776
these philosophical causes combined with
British taxation set the stage for the
revolution on the screen now are
questions for this topic pause
now I'll put the answers on the screen
now
see you in the next one